University Scrapbook Collection 1988.0028
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
University Scrapbook Collection
undated, 1884-1998
1988.0028
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
53.0 Linear feet
The scrapbooks were created by individuals and entitities associated with the University of Connecticut and maintained as a separate collection because of format requirements.
Various.
History
In April 1881, the Connecticut General Assembly established the Storrs Agricultural School after accepting a gift of 170 acres of land, several frame buildings, and money from Charles and Augustus Storrs. The School opened on 28 September 1881, with twelve students in the first class. Before the turn of the century there were two name changes ( Storrs Agricultural College 1893, Connecticut Agricultural College 1899 ). In 1933, two years after the institution celebrated its fiftieth anniversary, it became Connecticut State College, a name more in keeping with its steady advances and broadened mission. Six years later, in 1939, the General Assembly designated the institution the University of Connecticut, an acknowledgment of the institution's developing importance to the State in graduate and professional education, research and public service.
Scope and Content
The collection contains scrapbooks documenting programs, activities, events and individuals associated with the University of Connecticut.
Arrangement
The scrapbooks are arranged chronologically.
Individuals and entitities associated with the scrapbooks include:
University of Connecticut (1988_0028)
University of Connecticut, School of Pharmacy (1993_0077)
Charles G. Hall (1979_0006)
Mansfield (CT) League of Women Voters (2005_0159)
Barbara I. Potterton (2003_0146)
Dwight J. Scott (1998_0128)
Irene Saxton Smith (2001_0092)
Jeannette Stone (1998_0246)
Randolph and Beatrice Whaples (1989_0049)
American Association of University Women, Connecticut Chapter Records (1988-0003)
Beatrice Freedman Ashmore (2009_0110)
Agatha Arnone Shepherd (2012-0019)
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to the University's history. A significant portion of these items are drawn from the University Memorabilia Collection. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Restrictions on Access
The collection is open and available for research.
Custodial History
Items in the collection may have orginally been offered to, held by or stored in other divisions of the University before final transfer to the University Archives.
Acquisition Information
Materials in the collection have been donated or transferred to, or otherwise acquired by, Archives & Special Collections over time.
Connecticut Agricultural College.; Connecticut State College.; Storrs Agricultural College (Conn.).; Storrs Agricultural School (Conn.).; University of Connecticut.; Connecticut; Storrs (Conn.); Universities and colleges
- Series I: Scrapbooks, undated, 1884-1998
  - 1988_0028_12, 1884-1931
  - 1979_0006_1, 1914-1918
  - 1998_0128_1, 1916-1927
  - 1988_0028_10, 1916-1942
  - 1988_0028_48 ( Randall, Arthur J., School of Agriculture, 1918), 1917-1918
  - 1988_0028_39 ( Alcott, George B.), 1917-1919
  - 1988_0028_21 ( Belden, Robert J.), 1917-1920
  - 1988_0028_26 ( Belden, Robert J.), 1918-1920
  - 1988_0028_24 ( Himes, Norman), 1918-1920
  - 1988_0028_22 ( Abbe, Raymond C.), 1919-1922
  - 1988_0028_23 ( Howe, Flora), 1921-1922
  - 1988_0028_1, 1921-1935
  - 1988_0028_15, 1921-1949
  - 1988_0028_38 ( Lorentzon, Arthur), 1924-1926
  - 1989_0049_1, 1924-1926
  - 1993_0077_1, 1925-1927
  - 2001_0092_1, 1925-1929
  - 1993_0077_2, 1925-1959
  - 2003_0146_1, 1931-1932
  - 1988_0028_8, 1931-1933
  - 1993_0077_3, 1931-1937
  - 1988_0028_13 (Alumni Association--pennant, aerial photo), 1931-1939
  - 2003_0146_2, 1932-1933
  - 1988_0028_6, 1933
  - 2003_0146_3, 1933-1934
  - 2003_0146_4, 1934-1935
  - 1988_0028_41 (Class of 1943--Diesel), 1939-1940
  - 1998_0246_1, 1940-1941
  - 1988_0028_40 (Class of 1943--Diesel), 1941
  - 1998_0246_2, 1941-1942
  - 1993_0077_4, 1941-1944
  - 1997_0109_1 (Archery), 1941-1944
  - 1988_0028_7 (Alumni Association), 1941-1951
  - 1988_0028_42 (Class of 1943--Diesel), 1942-1943
  - 2009_0110 ( Beatrice Freedman Ashmore), 1942-1946
  - 1998_0246_3, 1943-1944
  - 1997_0087_4, 1943-1951
  - 1998_0246_4, 1944-1945
  - 1993_0077_5, 1944-1947
  - 1988_0028_18 (Farm Safety Program), 1945
  - 1993_0077_6, 1946-1950
  - 1988_0028_27 (Hartford Campus), 1946-1979
  - 1988_0028_3, ca. 1950
  - 1988_0028_16 ( Hoskin, Margery B.), 1950-1952
  - 2005_0159_1, 1950-1970
  - 1988_0028_37 ( Olin, Toby Jacobs), 1951-1954
  - 1988_0028_11 ( Hoskin, Margery B.), 1952-1954
  - 1988_0028_45 (Delta Epsilon Phi), 1952-1955
  - 1997_0087_3, 1952-1957
  - 1993_0077_7, 1952-1959
  - 1988_0028_17 ( Cecil, Marianna), 1953
  - 1988_0028_43 (predominantly athletics), 1954-1959
  - 1988_0028_44 (Delta Epsilon Phi Delta Pi Family Album), 1954-1964
  - 1988_0028_25 (Women's Recreation Association), 1955-1957
  - 1988_0028_47 (Delta Pi formerly Delta Epsilon Phi), 1955-1958
  - 1997_0087_2, 1957-1962
  - 1988_0028_9 (Delta Pi Pledge Class), 1958
  - 1988_0028_46 (Delta Pi Pledge Class), 1958
  - 1988_0028_4 (Jorgensen Auditorium), 1958-1961
  - 1988_0028_28 (Hartford Campus), 1959-1962
  - 1988_0028_14 (Women's Recreation Association), 1959-1962
  - 1993_0077_8, 1960-1964
  - 1988_0028_19 (Delta Pi 10th Anniversary), 1961
  - 1988_0028_5 (Jorgensen Auditorium), 1961-1962
  - 1997_0087_1, 1962-1968
  - 1988_0028_2 (Jorgensen Auditorium), 1964-1965
  - 1988_0028_29, 1965-1966
  - 1993_0077_9, 1965-1969
  - 1988_0028_20 (Jorgensen Auditorium), 1965-1967
  - 1988_0028_30, 1966-1968
  - 1988_0028_31, 1968-1969
  - 1988_0028_32, 1969-1970
  - 2005_0159_2, 1971-1991
  - 1988_0028_33, 1971-1972
  - 1988_0028_34, 1973-1974
  - 1988_0028_35, 1975-1976
  - 1988_0028_36, 1977-1981
  - 2005_0159_3, 1991-1997
  - 1988-0003_1, 1995-1998
  - 2005_0159_4, 1997-2003
  - 2012_0019_1 ( Agatha Arnone Shepherd), 1950-1954
  - 2008_0039_1 ( Louis E. Marshat), 1917-1962
  - 2012_0112_1 (Priscilla Champlin), 1934-1937; 2 volumes
  - 2012_0045_1 (Althea Davis, 1938), 1934-1937 (Volume 2012_0045_1)
  - 2013_0037_1 ( Eleanor May Aspinwall, 1938), 1914-1916